[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to section 2
您好，欢迎来到第2节
of lesson 2.
第二课
In this part we're going to talk about what a stream
在这一部分中，我们将讨论什么是流
actually is and the individual elememts of the stream
实际上是流的各个元素
that create the structure of it.
创造了它的结构。
If you look at the overview of a stream at a high level,
如果您从较高的角度看待流的概述，
essentially what we're dealing with is an abstraction
本质上，我们正在处理的是一种抽象
for specifying aggregate computations.
用于指定聚合计算。
That kind of sounds complicated but it's essentially what we've already seen
这种声音听起来很复杂，但这实质上是我们已经看到的
in earlier part of the course, where we taking a collection of data
在课程的较早部分，我们收集数据
and we want to specify how we want process that collection data.
并且我们要指定如何处理该收集数据。
We use the example where we were looking for
我们使用我们正在寻找的示例
student who got the highest score, or what highest score a student
得分最高的学生，或学生得分最高的学生
got in 2011. Thats an aggregate computation because we're taking that
是在2011年。那是一个汇总计算，因为我们采用了
collection data and looking for one particular value in there.
收集数据并在那里寻找一个特定的值。
The important things about
关于重要的事情
a stream are that, whilst you might
一个流是，虽然你可能
be tempted to think a bit as a data structure
倾向于将其视为数据结构
and certainly when we talk about the elements must remain that way that it
当然，当我们谈论这些要素时，必须保持这种方式
works
作品
it does look very much like a data structure, it's not.
它看起来确实很像数据结构，不是。
The data structure is just contained,
数据结构只是包含在内，
if we have a collection, is it a list, is it a set, is it a
如果我们有一个集合，是一个列表，是一个集合，是一个
hash map, or whatever. That's the data structure. The stream itself
哈希图，或其他。那就是数据结构。流本身
is just a way of defining how we process that as
只是定义我们如何处理的方式
sequence elements and one other things which is quite important
顺序元素和一件非常重要的事情
about streams is that they can be infinite.
关于流的是它们可以是无限的。
So there's no restriction in terms of how many elements
因此，对多少元素没有限制
stream can have, it can be and infinite stream which will
流可以有，它可以是无限流
carry on for ever and how we terminate that stream, how we get out of that
永远进行下去，以及我们如何终止该流，如何摆脱该流
stream
流
and is a little bit different to how we deal with loops.
与我们处理循环的方式有些不同。
We're used to having infinite loops in Java,
我们习惯于在Java中使用无限循环，
where we don't know how many times a loop needs to be executed.
我们不知道循环需要执行多少次。
What we do is we create a loop it says while true
我们要做的是创建一个循环，其内容为true
do something and then we have a test if X is
做某事，然后我们测试X是否为
10 break and we can break out of the loop.
10分，我们可以跳出循环。
We can't do that in streams; there's no concept breaking out of the stream
我们不能在流中做到这一点；没有任何概念可以突破
because there's no concept of
因为没有概念
loop. Remember in section 1 we talked about
环。还记得我们在第1节中谈到的
functional programming verses imperative programming but we'll come
函数式编程与命令式编程相比，但我们会来
back to how we can use an infinite stream
回到我们如何使用无限流
and how we can terminate that infinite stream in much the same way as we would
以及我们如何以与我们几乎相同的方式终止该无限流
with an infinite loop. What the stream allows us to do is to
无限循环流允许我们做的是
create a simple description of how we want to
创建一个关于我们想要如何的简单描述
perform these computations and
执行这些计算并
for the code and make the library code.
代码，并制作库代码。
It's very useful because it allows us to
这非常有用，因为它使我们能够
have opportunities to optimize how that code works.
有机会优化该代码的工作方式。
What we do is we can take complex operations
我们要做的是可以进行复杂的操作
and we can fuse together certain operations so that they happen together
我们可以将某些操作融合在一起，以便它们一起发生
rather than having to happen individually. That way it can be
而不是必须单独进行。这样就可以了
more efficient. We can use
更高效。我们可以用
lazy evaluation so that we're not having to evaluate every element in a
懒惰的评估，这样我们就不必评估一个
collection if we don't need to
如果我们不需要收集
and as we've already seen we can apply
正如我们已经看到的，我们可以申请
parallelism to how we do these things
与我们如何做这些事情平行
because with functional programming remember there's no
因为使用函数式编程时请记住没有
reliance on order execution which means that we can
依靠订单执行，这意味着我们可以
use parallel processing in the exact same way as
使用与以下完全相同的方式进行并行处理
sequential processing without changing results.
顺序处理而不会改变结果。
Now in terms of
现在来讲
stream you can think about it as
流，您可以考虑一下
representing a pipeline, where we're processing data.
代表我们正在处理数据的管道。
One end of that pipeline
该管道的一端
is what we call the source, so on the left hand side we have a source
是我们所说的来源，所以在左侧我们有一个来源
of our stream and that will be a set of
的流，这将是一组
elements of something that we want to process.
我们要处理的东西的元素。
It could come from a collection, it could come from a network connection, it could come from
它可能来自集合，可能来自网络连接，也可能来自
wherever we want,
无论我们在哪里
but it's a source of elements that we're going to process
但这是我们要处理的元素的来源
and that's what stream it is. It's a stream of elements that are going to be
那就是它的流。这将是一系列元素
processed.
处理。
What we do is we take that stream source,
我们要做的是获取流源，
that stream and we pass it into zero or more
该流，然后将其传递到零或更多
intermediate operations. An intermediate operation
中间作业。中间操作
is one that takes as input stream and generates
是作为输入流并生成的一个
as output a stream.
作为输出流。
That way we can take the output of one intermediate
这样我们就可以获取一个中间产品的输出
operation and feed it to the input of
操作并将其输入到
another intermediate operation. As you can see in the diagram
另一个中间操作。如您在图中所见
to blue boxes representing intermediate operations.
代表中间操作的蓝色框。
Stream in, stream out. Connect the stream output of the first operation
流入，流出。连接第一个操作的流输出
to the input of the second intermediate operation. Once we've
到第二个中间操作的输入。一旦我们
done all the intermediate processing that we want,
完成了我们想要的所有中间处理，
we need to terminate that stream,
我们需要终止该流
we need the other end of our pipeline
我们需要管道的另一端
and to do that we have a terminal operation.
为此，我们进行了终端操作。
A terminal operation takes as input a stream
终端操作将流作为输入
and doesn't generate a stream as an output.
并且不会生成流作为输出。
What it generates is either explicit result
它产生的是明确的结果
in the form of a value or collection or something,
以价值或collections之类的形式，
or it produces a side effect and a side effect could be something as simple as
或产生副作用，而副作用可能像
printing a message to say
打印一条消息说
found something. So these are three
找到了东西。所以这是三个
main components of our stream: source,
我们信息流的主要组成部分：来源，
intermediate operation, terminal operation. Here's an example
中间操作，终端操作。这是一个例子
of a stream and how we're going to use it. Ihis case
流以及我们将如何使用它。他的情况
I have set of transactions. From that set of transactions,
我有交易集。从那组交易中，
I need to create a stream source so I call the stream method on that,
我需要创建一个流源，因此我要在其上调用stream方法，
and that returns a stream.
然后返回流。
We pass that stream into
我们将该流传递到
an intermediate operation this case it's filter where we going to
在这种情况下的中间操作是过滤器
only select that buyers who were in London
只选择那些在伦敦的买家
from all the transactions that we have. We then pass that
从我们所有的交易中。然后我们通过
to another intermediate operation called mapToInt and that's going to create a
到另一个名为mapToInt的中间操作，它将创建一个
stream of
的流
integers, or ints, which are the prices
整数或整数，即价格
of those transactions. We'll talk more about the primitive
这些交易中。我们将更多地讨论原始
verses object representation later in this lesson. Once we've got that stream all
在本课后面的章节中介绍对象表示。一旦我们有了所有的流
transaction values, prices, we pass that
交易价格，价格，我们通过
into it terminal operation
进入终端操作
which is to sum all those values,
将所有这些值相加
and that will then return back to total
然后将返回到总计
all the total transactions
全部交易
for buyers who were in London. Now
对于在伦敦的买家。现在
in terms the terminal operations what we need to understand is that
在终端操作方面，我们需要了解的是
although when we talk about stream we say, well you take a stream from the
尽管当我们谈论流时，我们说，嗯，您从
source you pass to an intermediate
您传递给中间人的来源
operation that creates new stream and passes it
创建新流并将其传递的操作
on and so on. That's a good way of understanding
等等。那是理解的好方法
essentially how things work but is not
本质上是如何运作的，但不是
the way things will actually be implemented in the library code
实际在库代码中实现的方式
so that the pipeline itself is only evaluated
这样就只能评估管道本身
when a terminal operation is called and
当终端操作被调用时
all the operations that we have in that pipeline
该管道中的所有操作
are either going to be executed sequentially or their going to be
要么顺序执行，要么
executed in parallel and will come back to
并行执行，然后返回
talk about this in lesson 3, when we talk about parallel streams in more
在第3课中讨论这一点，当我们在更多内容中讨论并行流时
detail.
详情。
But essentially either its executed sequentially
但实质上是按顺序执行
or it's executed parallel because we don't do anything until we get to the terminal
还是并行执行，因为直到到达终端我们什么都不做
operations
运作
does mean that we can merge together some of the intermediate
确实意味着我们可以将一些中间产品合并在一起
operations. That way we can avoid redundant passes
操作。这样我们就可以避免多余的通行证
on the data, we can also do things like short-circuiting
根据数据，我们还可以做短路之类的事情
as its called, so if we want to find 00:08:23,019 --&gt; 00:08:26,199 first element that let's say greater than 10
就像它的名字一样，所以如果我们想找到140 00：08：23,019-&gt; 00：08：26,199第一个元素大于10
and you got 1000 elements in your input stream
在输入流中有1000个元素
then you don't need to worry about processing all of them
那么您不必担心处理所有这些
once you found one that is actually more than 10. So you can do
一旦找到一个实际上大于10的
short-circuiting, you can do lazy evaluation where you actually putting the results through
短路时，您可以进行懒惰评估，实际将结果通过
as you need them rather processing everything ahead of time.
因为您需要他们，而不是提前处理所有事情。
Internally there are a number of characteristics to be used by
在内部，有许多特征可供使用
stream. As a developer you don't need to worry about this, but it's just what
流。作为开发人员，您不必担心这一点，但这就是事实
can be used internally in the library code to optimize things.
可以在库代码内部用于优化事物。
So for example, one of the characteristics of a stream is whether
因此，例如，流的特征之一是
its distinct.
其独特之处。
So we mark it if we know that there are no
因此，如果我们知道没有
duplicate elements
重复元素
in that stream. If you pass a stream
在那流中。如果您通过流
to a method, distinct, and
方法，与众不同
the streams already distinct, then we don't have to do anything, because we know
stream已经不同了，那么我们就不需要做任何事情，因为我们知道
its distinct there's no
它与众不同
extra work to do. We don't process it again once we know it is distinct.
额外的工作要做。一旦知道它是与众不同的，我们将不再对其进行处理。
So to summarize section 2
所以总结一下第二节
you can think of a stream, like I said, like a pipeline.
您可以像我说的那样想到一条流，就像一条管道。
At one end is the source for the data gets passed through
一端是数据通过的源
0 or more intermediate operations. I mean when you want to
0个或更多中间操作。我的意思是当你想
terminate that stream you have a terminal operation. The way that processes data,
终止该流，您可以执行终端操作。处理数据的方式，
even though it's processing set of data is it doesn't use explicit
即使它正在处理数据集也不使用显式
loops, so this is quite important and comes back to the
循环，所以这非常重要，然后回到
difference between imperative behavior verses functional behavior. There is no
命令式行为与函数式行为之间的差异。没有
explicit loop;
显式循环
the loop is implicit in terms of
循环是隐式的
all the library code that you're using. What this means
您正在使用的所有库代码。这是什么意思
is that it does make it very easy for us to turn a stream for being sequential
是它确实使我们很容易将流变为顺序流
stream into a parallel stream
流到并行流
without worrying about will it change the way the code works, will it change results
不用担心会改变代码的工作方式，是否会改变结果
being generated.
正在生成。
And that is the end of section 2.
到第二节结束。